# SOUVIK SARKAR

## Senior Technical Writer

 $sounix000@gmail.com \diamond (+91) 6360229130 \diamond Website$ 

#### **OVERVIEW**

Technical Writer with 8 years of experience documenting software and APIs for developers and administrators, backed by 4 years of experience as a developer. I develop deep technical content for an optimal developer experience using the docs-as-code paradigm and open-source tools.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Python, Bash, C/C++, Asm
Markup DocBook XML, AsciiDoc
Deployment Docker, Kubernetes
Cloud Google Cloud Platform
VCS Git (GitHub, GitLab)
Images/Diagrams Inkscape, Mermaid.js
Code/Text Editors VS Code, Vim

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

SUSE March 2023 - Present

Senior Technical Writer

- · Maintain the SUSE Linux Enterprise guides for performance tuning, virtualization, security, and compliance certifications.
- · Research, plan, and contribute to transitioning from monolithic guides to topic-based modular documentation for SUSE Linux Enterprise.
- · Collaborate with engineers, release managers, and product managers to realign the SUSE Linux Enterprise documentation with technical and business expectations.
- · Interface with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge base articles.
- · Participate in peer reviews and mentor new technical writers in the team.
- · Technologies/Tools: SUSE Linux Enterprise, OpenSUSE Leap, Bash, Python, C, Assembly, DocBook XML, AsciiDoc, GitHub, GitLab, VS Code, Vim, JIRA, Confluence Wiki

Red Hat November 2020–March 2023

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for OpenShift CI/CD Pipelines, including triaging issues, creating documentation plans, and deciding content strategy.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated with content strategists and product managers to realign product documentation with upstream documentation.
- · Interfaced with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge-base articles.
- · Data analyzed to improve documentation coverage, flow, architecture, findability, and accessibility.
- · Technologies/Tools: Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Fedora Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, AWS, Golang, Bash, AsciiDoc, Markdown, Lucidchart, GitHub, GitLab, VS Code, Vim, JIRA, Tableau, Google Sheets

#### **Ribbon Communications**

January 2019–November 2020

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for SBC Core, resulting in improved customer satisfaction ratings.
- · Developed documents such as CLI reference and REST API user guide.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated to revamp the internal style guide for easier onboarding of new technical writers.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, C, Bash, OpenStack, AWS, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, JIRA

#### FusionCharts (Infosoft Global Pvt. Ltd.)

March 2018-January 2019

Technical Content Writer

- · Developed and reviewed sample applications, code snippets, and content for developer documentation.
- · Implemented automation scripts to improve the operational efficiency of pre-release workflows.
- · Worked with the engineering and marketing teams to create and publish technical articles on third-party websites and blogs.
- Technologies/Tools: macOS, JavaScript (Node.js, Vue.js, React.js), VS Code, Markdown, Lucidchart, GitHub, Trello

Tata Elxsi

June 2016–March 2018

Consultant Technical Writer

Contractor for Ribbon Communications

- · Created and maintained Quick Start tutorials, API guides, User guides, and Release Notes.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, C, Bash, OpenStack, AWS, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, JIRA

#### Agaze Technologies

September 2015–May 2016

Software Engineer

- · Developed internal and client-facing applications, focusing on back-end implementation.
- · <u>Technologies/Tools</u>: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Django, Flask), PostgreSQL, JavaScript (Node.js, React.js), Google Cloud Platform (App Engine).

## Freelance/Self-employed

July 2012-August 2015

 $Web\ Developer$ 

- · Developed websites, administered systems, and wrote technical content for blogs as a ghostwriter.
- · Technologies/Tools: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Django, Flask), MySQL, JavaScript, Google Sheets

#### RECOGNITIONS

**Red Hat** - Several peer-to-peer awards from team members (including engineering) for collaboration and commitment to excellence.

Ribbon Communications - Motivate Award (2019-2020) for extraordinary performance.

Tata Elxsi - Customer Appreciation Award (2016-2017) based on client recommendation.

## **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Technology

2014